Ravi Damuluri

+44 7733598948 | ravidamuluri1@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Resourceful, dedicated and safety focused professional construction manager with 8 years of experience managing large-scale construction projects. Influential leader, skilled at completing projects within timeframe and budget. Skilled at quality control and ability to communicate clearly and resolve problems to enable project success. Proactive and excited to collaborate with like-minded individuals to achieve goals.

Key Skills

- Client management
- Health and Safety requirements
- Construction management

- Project coordination
- Project management
- Software skills including AutoCAD, StaadPro, MS Office Suite

Education

Rajiv Gandhi University of Knowledge Technologies - Basar, India | Bachelor of Technology Civil Engineering, 2014

Certifications

• CSCS Black Card [in progress]

Experience

CONSTRUCTION PROJECT MANAGER | 01/2020 - 09/2022

Royal Zanzibar Beach Resort - Tanzania

- Closely monitored construction progress to ensure project advancement, holding regular update meetings with key stakeholders.
- Implemented high health and safety standards to enable continued staff wellbeing and compliance with CDM regulations.
- Maintained safe work environment with zero accidents or lost workdays.
- Resolved issues during construction and commissioning phases to maintain tight schedules and budget levels.
- Managed general contractors and reported project progress to project management for stakeholder updates.
- Maintained payroll data, attendance records and delivered materials to job site on time and in good condition.
- Completed the project on time and within allocated budget.

SENIOR CIVIL ENGINEER | 03/2017 - 03/2019

Dezo Civil Contractors Cooperation - Tanzania

- Oversaw development and construction of a 15 storey beach resort hotel facility.
- Inspected work at job sites to evaluate ongoing work, identify errors and initiate corrective actions to keep projects on schedule.
- Directed surveyors, drafters and junior engineers through project stages to successful completion.
- Used engineering judgment to appraise different options and recommend most suitable choice for issues.

- Liaised with internal and external stakeholders to communicate civil design.
- Delivered quality control and safety management during construction.
- Verified consistent delivery of high-quality work across structure construction.
- Controlled project budget, implemented cost monitoring and restructured repetitive processes to cut costs and maximise profits.

SITE ENGINEER | 09/2015 - 02/2017

Dezo Civil Contractors Cooperation - Tanzania

- Oversaw extension and renovation of high rise commercial blocks from beginning to end and coordinated stakeholder review and handover to clients.
- Assessed standards against agreed measures to achieve quality assurance.
- Generated reports detailing site activities, incidents and resolutions.
- Supervised and monitored project subcontractors and labour teams.
- Completed site surveys, marked locations and oversaw construction of various projects.
- Coordinated engineers and construction professionals to meet varied project demands.
- Presented project plans and updates to stakeholders for review and decision-making.
- Rectified engineering errors and faults quickly to meet project KPIs.

GRADUATE ENGINEER | 08/2014 - 09/2015

Felguera Gruas India Private Ltd - India

- Produced technical calculations to support design work using StaadPro software.
- Sketched outline designs and used AutoCAD programs to provide detailed design and specifications.
- Developed and implemented engineering solutions for project and design issues.
- Designed fixings for various structural materials, including concrete, brick and stone.
- Worked effectively with architects and clients to develop safe and sustainable designs.